Finding Aid for College of Engineering (University of Michigan) publications, 1873-2015
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sub-Unit Publications
  - Office for the Study of Automotive Transportation
    - Reports
      - Review of Operations Through August 1980 and Financial Plans, [1980] (Box 16)
  - Office of the Dean
    - Brochures
      - 1971-1972 (Box 16)
      - Safety and Emergency Information, 1991 (Box 16)
    - Bulletins
      - Ingenor, 1966-1972 no. 1-9, 9 folders (Box 16)
      - Technium, 1974-1979, 2 folders (Box 16)
      - TechniUM+, no. 1-5, 1975-1976 (Box 16)
      - Technium+, no. 6-18, 1976-1980, 3 folders (Box 16)
    - Newsletters
      - Alumni Notes, 1978 (Box 16)
      - News, 1967-1973, 6 folders (Box 16)
      - Newsletter, 1966-1972, 11 folders (Box 17)
      - Newsliner, 1972-1975, 5 folders (Box 17)
  - Office of Graduate Education
    - Newsletters
      - The Term Paper, 2000 (Box 17)
  - Program in Manufacturing
    - Annual Reports and Brochures 1993, undated (Box 17)
  - Project of the Use of Computers in Engineering Education
    - Annual Reports
      - Integration of Electronic Computers into the Undergraduate Engineering Educational Program, 1960 (Box 17)
      - Second Annual Report, 1961 (Box 17)
      - Final Report, 1963 (Box 17)
    - Reports
      - Analog Computer Fundamentals by Silvio O. Navarro, 1962 (Box 17)
  - Research Excellence Fund
    - Proposals
      - An Application by the University of Michigan to the Research Excellence and Economic Development Fund, 1985 (Box 18)
      - An Application by the University of Michigan to the Research Excellence Fund for Continued Support of Three Centers of Excellence in Engineering, 1987-1989, 3 folders (Box 18)
      - A Proposal to the Michigan Research Excellence Fund to Establish a Center of Scholarly Excellence in Advanced Electronics and Optics Technology, 1985 (Box 18)
      - A Proposal to the Michigan Research Excellence Fund to Establish a Center of Scholarly Excellence in Complex Manufacturing Technology, 1985 (Box 18)
    - Reports
      - Michigan: The State and the University, A Partnership for Economic Growth, 1990 (Box 18)
      - Progress Report: The University of Michigan, College of Engineering Programs Sponsored by the Research Excellence Fund During the Period July 1, 1987 through April 30, 1988, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Robotics Industrial Affiliates Program
    - Brochures undated (Box 18)
  - School of Mines
    - Bulletins
      - Annual Announcement of the School of Mines, 1875 (Box 18)
  - Science Engineering
    - Brochures 1955-1991 (Box 18)
  - Seminar on the Theory of Structures
    - Proceedings 1931-1933, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Summer Session
    - Bulletins
      - Advanced Courses, 1929 (Box 18)
      - Electronics Institute, 1937 (Box 18)
      - Special Announcement, 1920 (Box 18)
    - Texts
      - Nuclear Reactors and Radiations in Industry
        - vol. 1-3 1956, 3 folders (Box 18)
        - vol. 1 and 3 1957, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Engineering Global Leadership Honors Program (EGL)
      - Manuals
        - EGL Curriculum Guide, 1995 (Box 18)
  - Undergraduate Curriculum Development in Engineering Program
    - Proposals
      - Engineering Education and Design in the Computer Workstation Era, 1988 (Box 18)
  - Undergraduate Curriculum Task Force
    - Reports
      - Michigan Curriculum 2000 Proposed Changes to the Undergraduate Curriculum, Final Report to the Faculty and Students, 1996 (Box 18)
  - Urban Technological and Environmental Planning, Program in
    - Brochures 1983 (Box 18)
- Topical Publications
  The Topical Publications series (1.3 linear feet) contains publications which relate to important events, such as the "Centennial Celebration" of the college celebrated from 1953 to 1954. Convocations, including one honoring Michigan's astronauts, are documented in this series. Under "Faculty," researchers will find publications describing various service awards given to the College of Engineering faculty, and brochures introducing new faculty and tenure recipients in the period from 1992 to 1994. There are invitations, manuals and programs dating from 1983 to 2002 describing the graduation exercises of the College of Engineering. Brochures documenting "Technirama" from 1963 to 1969 and "Tech Day" from 1981 to 1993 are found in this series.
  - Awards 1975-1980, undated (Box 18)
  - Centennial Celebration
    - Addresses
      - Addresses Given at the Centennial of Engineering Education at the University of Michigan, October 23-24, 1953 (Box 19)
    - Citations
      - Citations: 1853-1953 Centennial of Engineering, 1953 (Box 19)
    - Programs 1953 (Box 19)
  - Convocation
    - Addresses
      - Fourth Annual Engineering Convocation, 1965 (Box 19)
    - Programs 1964 (Box 19)
    - Special Convocations
      - Convocation Honoring Astronauts, 1965 (Box 19)
  - Engineering Ethics
    - Texts
      - An Introduction to the Teaching of Engineering Ethics by R.S. Swinton, 1948 (Box 19)
  - Faculty
    - Awards
      - 1938-E Distinguished Service Award Recipients, 1960-1988 (Box 19)
      - Chiang Technology Achievement Award to Professor Shien-Ming Wu, 1992 (Box 19)
      - Collegiate Professorship Recognition, 2001 (Box 19)
      - Endowed Professorship Recognition
        - 1992-1993 (Box 19)
        - 1999-2000 (Box 19)
      - Faculty Honors Assembly, 1980-1985 (Box 19)
      - Faculty Honors Dinner Dance, 1993-2002, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Faculty Honors Recognition and Holiday Supper, 1990 (Box 19)
    - Brochures
      - The University of Michigan College of Engineering Introduces Its New Faculty, 1993-1994 (Box 19)
    - Memorials
      - Programs 1992 in memory of Professor Sam Wu (Box 19)
    - Tenure Recipients
      - Brochures 1992-1994 (Box 19)
  - Faraday Christmas Lecture
    - Programs 1970-1971, undated (Box 19)
  - Graduation Exercises
    - Invitations 1985-1986, 1996 (Box 19)
    - Manuals
      - General Information, 1994-1995 (Box 19)
      - Information About Graduation, 2001 (Box 19)
    - Programs 1983-2002, 18 folders (Box 19)
  - Mentor System
    - Brochures
      - The Mentor System in the Department of Engineering, 1914-1915 (Box 20)
  - Sesquicentennial Celebration
    - Brochures 1967 (Box 20)
  - Staff Service Awards
    - Brochures
      - Excellence in Staff Service Awards, 1993 (Box 20)
  - Tech Day
    - Brochures
      - 1978-1981 (Box 20)
      - 1986-1993, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - E-Mail Printouts 1997 (Box 20)
  - Technirama
    - Brochures 1963-1969 (Box 20)
  - Wilson Student Team Project Center
    - Programs
      - Wilson Student Team Project Center Dedication Ceremony, 1999 (Box 20)
- Student Publications
  - General Student Publications
    The Student Publications series (.7 linear feet) is organized with general student publications, such as the Anvil, Datum, and Engin, followed by publications, chiefly brochures and programs, of specific organizations such as the Society of Black Engineers, Society of Women Engineers (SWE), and Tau Beta Pi. The Michigan Technic, published from 1888 through 1989, is cataloged separately under the call number FImu F3h.
    - Newsletters
      - Anvil includes charter, 1985-1988 vol. 1-7, 8 folders (Box 20)
      - Datum, 1968-1979, 11 folders (Box 20)
      - Engin 168, 1990-1993, 3 folders (Box 20)
      - Student Newsletter, 1972 (Box 20)
      - Untitled, 1985 (Box 20)
  - Specific Student Organizations
    - American Society of Engineering Education Student Chapter
      - Announcements (e-mail printouts) 1997 (Box 20)
    - Michigan Engineering Consulting Club
      - Announcements (e-mail printouts) 1997 (Box 20)
    - Michigan Student Society of Professional Engineers
      - Annual Reports 1988-1989 (Box 20)
      - Brochures undated (Box 20)
    - Pi Tau Sigma
      - Newsletters (Box 20)
      - The Gearhead Gazette, 1994 (Box 20)
    - Society of Black Engineers
      - Brochures undated (Box 20)
      - Emblem undated (Box 20)
      - Newsletters 1971 (Box 20)
    - Society of Women Engineers
      - Brochures 1992-1995 (Box 20)
      - Directories
        - Resume Book, 1988-1989 (Box 20)
      - Manuals
        - The UM Survival Guide to the Engineering Universe, 1992 (Box 20)
      - Newsletters
        - Alumni News, 1994 (Box 20)
        - Corporate Newsletter, 1994 (Box 20)
        - SWE, 1996 (Box 20)
        - SWE Specialist, 2000 (Box 20)
      - Programs
        - Awards Banquet, 1994-1995 (Box 20)
      - Career Fair
        - Flyers 1994-1996 (Box 20)
        - Programs 1992-1993, 2000 (Box 20)
      - Professional Development Day
        - Flyers 1994 (Box 20)
      - Student Conference
        - Programs 1982-1991 (Box 20)
      - Summer Engineering Exploration Program
        - Brochures 1991-1992 (Box 20)
      - Symposium on Engineering
        - Flyers 1995 (Box 20)
    - Tau Beta Pi
      - Brochures 1971, 1985 (Box 20)
      - Constitution and By-Laws 1970 (Box 20)
      - Flyers undated (Box 20)
      - Manuals
        - Manual of Operations for Tau Beta Pi Engineering Convocation, 1963 (Box 20)
      - Newsletters
        - The Bent of Tau Beta Pi, 1967 (Box 20)
      - Programs 1967, 1981 (Box 20)
    - Volunteer Computer Corps
      - Newsletters
        - The Informa: Volunteer Computer Corps Newsletter, 1994 (Box 20)
  - Scrapbooks (Box 21)
    - 1991-1995, 3 volumes (Box 21)
      Located here from Box 6
- Archived College of Engineering Website
  The College of Engineering Archived Website series documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the College of Engineering. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as newsletters and course catalogs), and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, and the overall mission of the College. The website series is arranged chronologically, with captures from 2002 and 2003 stored on CD. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - Website capture May 15, 2002, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
    (Original URL http://www.engin.umich.edu)
  - Website capture June 23, 2003, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 2)
  - Archived College of Engineering home page 2010-[ongoing]
  - Archived websites related to the College of Engineering 2010-[ongoing]
Related Material
The publications for some individual departments have been processed separately, including those for:
Department of Aerospace Engineering
Department of Atmospheric, Oceanic and Space Sciences
Department of Chemical Engineering
Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering
Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science
Department of Industrial Operations and Engineering
Department of Materials Science and Engineering
Department of Mechanical Engineering and Applied Mechanics
Department of Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering
Department of Nuclear Engineering.